I need to get to acting school.
It's almost time for my lessons.
Itabashi Third Hospital
Listen to the doctors and stay in bed, okay?
Thank you, nurse.
Sheesh.
Rent-a-Girlfriend
Hello!
Oh, hey, Chizuru-chan.
Did we start already?
There are sixty-five students
in this acting school.
Nope, just about to.
Clown Wars
Showing now to packed houses!
Oh lord,
they coming!
Coming in
Go back to
your roots...
Only one or two get to sign
with an agency each year.
And even fewer actually get work.
Chizuru-chan, do you want
to get some grub with us?
Sorry, I've got rehearsals now.
Sorry about that!
Don't worry about it.
Chi-chan's incredible.
She never misses an acting lesson,
and she goes to all the courses
her agency signed her up for.
She visits her grandma in the
hospital twice every day.
And she goes to rehearsals.
Oh, and she takes two auditions a week.
How long is her day? Thirty hours?
Acting school costs 24,000 yen per month.
Even that's pretty reasonable, comparatively.
Yikes! I forgot to go to the bank!
Urk...
I gotta pay the fees this weekend, too.
This is a diet.
Beckoning Cat Troupe
Rehearsing
I learn a lot working with the troupe,
but you can find these
small ones everywhere.
Oh, how cruel!
Talent, luck, timing...
Without all of those,
you're not going to stand out.
I'm sorry!
Did you wait long?
Rental girlfriend work is great.
It pays well, and it lets
me choose my own hours.
I can use my free time for myself,
and it's great acting practice.
"Girlfriend and Me"
She hasn't been eating much lately.
I pretty much knew from the start,
from the moment I heard
my grandma's diagnosis.
Movie roles aren't easy to land.
I knew I'd never make it in time.
That's exactly why I made sure
I wouldn't have any regrets.
So that Grandma wouldn't have any, either.
Obata-san
Re: The BLB Movie Audition
There's no way she'll make it to release.
But if I can at least tell her I got picked...
Obata-san
Re: The BLB Movie Audition
If I can at least tell her
that dreams do come true...
The Big Love Bang
Obata-san
You didn't pass the BLB audition.
Better luck next time!
Obata-san
You didn't pass the BLB audition.
Better luck next time!
Got it.
Onward and upward!
I failed again.
What else can I even do?
Stop smirking and tell me,
Grandpa...
m 0 0 l 86 0 l 86 225 l 0 225
Years
Ago
What?!
You got into a fight with some boys because
they teased you for not having parents?!
Next time, tell 'em you've got a grandpa
who'll run circles around their dads!
m 0 0 l 200 0 l 200 100 l 0 100
Ichinose Sayuri
Age 70
Listen up, Chizuru!
m 0 0 l 216 0 l 216 60 l 0 60
Ichinose Katsuhito (73)
Your feelings will always get through!
Huh...
m 0 0 l 130 0 l 130 155 l 0 155
Seventh
Grade
m 0 0 l 130 0 l 130 155 l 0 155
Ichinose
Chizuru
Are you even listening?!
Chomping on
that ice cream...
All men are idiots.
Married 35 years,
and still madly in love
They've got their heads in the
clouds and can't face reality.
Say "ahh," Katsuhito-san.
They always put on airs
and are cowards deep down.
Your granddaughter's
right here...
And they're optimistic to a fault.
Listen here, Chizuru.
Dreams always come true.
But Liu Bei died of illness in Baidi Fortress,
and his son Liu Shan got the whole dynasty
wiped out by Sima Zhao of the Wei.
Wh-What are you saying?!
The Three Kingdoms
Their dream was passed on and laid the
foundation for the 160-year Jin Dynasty!
Huh... Sounds kinda forced.
You're so cynical.
But I love this story.
Oh, do you? I'm glad you get it, Chizuru!
I cut up some watermelon!
What? A hundred shrine visits?
That thing where you keep
running up and down the stairs?
Praying to the gods works!
The night before I proposed to Sayuri,
the gods took note of my raging emotions—
That's just superstition.
Hey, Chizuru!
chuckle       chuckle
Sit down! You need to learn a lesson!
What?
I loved books and movies even as a child.
I'd often go read in the
library on my days off,
and I also saved up my pocket
money to go the movies.
ba-dump ba-dump
I'd heard that my grandma
used to be an actress.
I'm not sure if that played a part...
But at some point,
I wanted to be like the people on the screen.
It was in ninth grade that I
decided to be an actress for real.
I-Is this...
Starring Otori Sayuri, winner
of Japan's Rising Star Award
One Thousand Cranes
Japanese Drama
Runtime
105 minutes
Wow, this takes me back!
You want to watch it with me?
How embarrassing!
What the hell would you know?!
Th-That's Grandma?!
She's a downright filthy liar!
Grandma was a prodigy.
Under the stage name "Otori Sayuri,"
she and her method acting, as they called it,
Give me back my son!
took the acting world by
storm in her very first role.
You know, your name was taken from
"Senbazuru," the title of this movie.
Your mother often used to say that,
like a thousand folded cranes,
she wanted you to grant
wishes and bring happiness.
My name...
That was when I learned that you don't
"have" dreams, they take you over.
One Thousand Cranes
Can I be like her someday, too?
You have rice on your face, Katsuhito-san.
I wanna be an actress.
An actress like Grandma.
Chizuru...
Chizuru, the world of acting isn't easy.
Well said, Chizuru! Is that your dream?!
You can do it!
I'm sure you can be a wonderful
actress like Sayuri!
Yeah!
You can do it, Chizuru!
You can do it!
Yeah!
But still, Chizuru...
You should go to college.
The world's changing fast, and
nobody knows what the future holds.
Okay, got it.
That said, I'm so happy that you
managed to say your dream out loud!
And here I thought you
were a cynical child...
Who? Me?
If you keep dreaming and work hard,
your dream will come true!
You have my full support until it does!
And I'm gonna see you perform on the
silver screen just like Sayuri did!
That's a promise, Chizuru!
Yeah.
Promise!
It's like the Oath of the Peach Garden!
True!
I'm off!
Morning
practice?
I'll give you
a ride in my taxi.
Thank you, Grandpa,
Theater Club
for telling me I could do it.
I'm gonna do it.
I'll be an actress.
Courses
1 Course             12,000 yen
2 Courses            18,000 yen
4 Courses            24,000 yen
Like Grandma,
I'm gonna be an amazing actress.
g
l
o
m
BROKE
I can't afford that.
I'm gonna show you two how
I look on the silver screen!
Asuka North High School
You said dreams come true,
that you'd support me....
Chizuru.
Mornin'.
Oh, good morning.
So thank you, Grandpa!
The truck driver was distracted
and jumped out on a red light.
Chizuru!
Operating
Will Grandpa be okay?
We don't know...
Operating
Chizuru?
Chizuru!
What? A hundred shrine visits?
Praying to the gods works!
Staying in the hospital
won't help save Grandpa!
What I can do for him right now
isn't sitting there and crying.
You said it yourself, Grandpa.
That the gods are watching over us.
If you keep dreaming and work hard,
your dream will come true!
That you'd see me become an actress.
Your feelings will always get through!
That dreams always come true!
You can do it, Chizuru!
Tell me one more time, Grandpa!
Grandpa...
Grandpa!
His brain suffered a lot of trauma.
He isn't coming to.
Tonight will be make or break.
I see...
Katsuhito-san!
Chizuru...
Remember what you said, Grandpa?
You said that you'd see me become
an actress, that I had your full support.
Did you know?
My name was taken from a
thousand folded cranes...
They make any wish come true.
So if I wish for it,
it will work like a charm.
Chizuru...
You said it yourself, Grandpa...
That if you keep wishing for it,
you can make any dream come true...
Katsuhito-san!
Grandpa!
How are his vitals?
No change!
Katsuhito-san! Katsuhito-san!
Grandpa!
...true.
...wish... true...
If you wish for it...
your dream...
will... come true...
Itabashi Third Hospital
Rent-a-Girlfriend
Say, Grandpa...
Did you lie to me?
Die you lie to me when you
said dreams come true?
If you did,
that's fine.
I know some wishes don't come true,
no matter how hard you try.
Obata-san
You didn't pass the BLB audition.
Better luck next time!
So... So...
Please!
Stop telling me my dreams will come true!
Yes?
It's me.
Open up.
Wha?
Ichinose
What is it? What do you want?
Hey!
Whoa, you can't come inside!
It's fine!
No, it isn't!
This project hasn't launched yet.
Making a Movie Starring Actress Ichinose Chizuru (Upcoming)
Look!
What is crowdfunding?
Crowd...funding?
This is a, uh, proposal?
A request to the site admins
to put up a project.
I looked into whether there were
any ways to make a movie quickly.
And it's crazy!
People start crowdfundings project and make
their own movies for, like, two million yen.
So many people do it!
It'd only take about a month to shoot, too.
That should be enough time, right?
W-Wait, calm down for a second.
I can't!
Theater Rental
Rent-a-Cinema
You can even, like, rent out a screen
at a movie theater these days.
With this, we can show Granny Sayuri!
She can see you shining on the screen!
Remember, I'm majoring in
business administration.
I'll get the funding,
so star in this!
I knew it.
Let's make a movie together!
Men are idiots.
Sorry.
I... need to think about it.
But we don't have time.
I know.
Just let me think.
I'm losing my mind!
But the clock's ticking...
What's Mizuhara doing?
Is she racking her brain?
Oh, what should I do?
What am I,
in heat?!
Why? Why'd it have to be a shower?!
Of course she'd have to think about it.
All I've ever done is show
her how pathetic I am.
Telling her I want to make a movie out
of the blue can't sound too convincing.
But I did my research.
The cost for making your own movie
depends on how ambitious you are,
but the equipment, manpower,
editing, and other costs
total up around two to three million yen.
Campfire, a massive crowdfunding site,
hosts around 200 similar projects per year.
Seventy percent of them reach their goal.
If you can make it to project
launch, it's not impossible.
Crowdfunding is, um... er...
Sumi-chan Memo
Crowdfunding is...
Blush...
Please Google it yourself!
That leaves the time problem.
Funding will take a month and a half.
Filming and editing should
take another month, maybe?
Honestly, I don't know if
Granny Sayuri has that long.
But...
So I at least want my grandma
to see me performing on screen.
That's my dream.
We just gotta go for it.
Do you have any better ideas,
Mizuhara?
Mizuhara!
Your Project
Title (Required)
Making a Movie Starring Actress Ichinose Chizuru
Description
Boasting breathtaking looks and incredible acting ability
What's a more professional
way to say "I think"?
I don't know if I can do this...
G
U
L
P
S-Sorry I sprang that on you.
I should've known it'd throw you off.
But it's your call, Mizuhara.
I'm not gonna force you.
Can you do it... really?
I don't want to waste the time I have left.
If you can't do it, or if you're
going to give up halfway,
tell me right now.
I can do it.
I'll show you that I can!
Men really are such idiots.
They put on airs and have
their heads in the clouds.
In this world, most dreams don't come true.
Then, please...
Help me make my movie.
So Grandma can see it.
You're on!
I'll do it!
I swear I'll see it through!
No matter what happens!
Come on, it's fine.
You're coming, right, Kazuya?
Not like you'll be the
star of the show, though.
Some other time.
And when will that be?
Karaoke Village
A Guide to
Making Movies
Hey, Kazuya-kun...
Rich in Courage
Nagomi Sake
Do I have no life?
That's my Sayutaso!
Itabashi Third Hospital
Is that so?
Yeah, yeah.
Café
Kanoir
Movin' and        Packin'
Let's make a movie together!
Then, please...
Help me make my movie.
What kind of face was I making then?
I'll do it!
Damn it, that idiot.
Enjoy the rest of this dream
with Diamond